

ABOUT

Engineering leader with 9 years experience developing and applying new technologies to deliver exceptional final products. Combines technical engineering capability with effective management techniques. Dedicated to driving rapid, advanced product development through meticulous oversight of team and hands-on participation.

CONTACT

PHONE: +91-9496361798

https://doitwithdk.github.io/

Linkedln: https://www.linkedin.com/in/deepakkarumathil

EMAIL: deepukjayan@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Software Architecture
- Product Head
- Mobile App Development
- Engineering Management
- Swift/Objective C
- Dart/Flutter

LANGUAGES

- English
- Hindi
- Malayalam
- Tamil

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication from Mahatma Gandhi University, Kerala.

DEEPAK

KARUMATHIL

DIRECTOR OF ENGINEERING

WORK HISTORY

Gnrgy | Director Of Engineering, Software (4 years 3 Mons) April 2016 – Present | Tel Aviv, Israel & Bengaluru, India

- Managing all software verticals by closely working with team managers and technical leads
- Very much hands on. (Swift/Objective C/Dart)
- Directly managing UI/UX and Mobile development team. Do development as well.
- Supports operations team when required and act as a bridge between multiple teams in the company
- 4 years back, took over the software side of Gnrgy
- Built a great and robust team of engineers that take care of all the R&D and daily charger network support nowadays
- Outlined, structured and developed all consumer facing applications
- Turned a bare shell floor to an awesome core engineering workspace at Bengaluru, India that fuel Gnrgy's operations.
- Managed day to day operations in India office

Care.com | Senior Software Engineer

April 2015 - April 2016 | Bengaluru, India

Worked for care.com at Hurits.

- Major role in the development and integration of "Care SDK"
- Actively involved in development of core Care app, Datenight app
- Involved in the architectural design and flow of mobile applications and development of the same

Managing Innovation & Technology | Senior Software Engineer November 2013 – April 2015 | Bengaluru, India

- Developed the core OTTO app using OpenCV

QBurst | Software Engineer

November 2011 - May 2013 | Thrissur, India

- Started as a junior team member
- Worked directly with Siemens on crucial medical projects and managed a small team of 2 members